<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>deep on sudo-code</title>
    <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/tags/deep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in deep on sudo-code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sudo-code7.github.io/tags/deep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Activation functions: Softmax and Sigmoid compared</title>
      <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/softmax-vs-sigmoid-activation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/softmax-vs-sigmoid-activation/</guid>
      <description>What are activation functions ? Activation functions are the key to Neural Networks (NN). They are the recipe to learn non-linear relationships in data, without them NNs would just be linear in nature. If you know the basics of logistic regression, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand the statement I made. I am planning to write another blog to cover activation functions from basics, therefore the focus here is just to compare softmax and sigmoid activation functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How hyper-parameters impact model training?  (with MLS-C01 focus)</title>
      <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/ai-ml-hyperparameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/ai-ml-hyperparameters/</guid>
      <description>What are hyperparameters ? In simple terms, hyperparameters are a set of knobs you can tune before starting the learning process in machine learning. When set to a specific values, the model has a specific performance. When the hyperparameters are set to new values, the model gets new performance values.
What is performance of a model? In any machine learning process, we want to optimize the objective-function: a fancy name for a function that evaluates model predictions v/s values provided during training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between Semantic and Instance Segmentation in Machine Learning?</title>
      <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/semantic-vs-instance-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/semantic-vs-instance-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy: Wikimedia
What is segmentation of image in machine learning? In the field of computer vision in machine learning, an image can be broken into segments by learning a mask for each segment. Image segmentation is used to locate object boundaries (lines, curves etc.) and assign a label to each pixel.
For example, this is from opencv documentation (watershed algorithm) where boundaries of a set of coins are learnt:
Original Image Semantic Segmentation Mask Learnt from Original Image  Sudo Exam Tip: Remember to recall image segmentation as a technique when there is a mention of classification of objects in an image at pixel level.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
