<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sap-c01 on sudo-code</title>
    <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/tags/sap-c01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sap-c01 on sudo-code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sudo-code7.github.io/tags/sap-c01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to pass MLS-C01 AWS Machine Learning Specialty Exam? How to Prepare? </title>
      <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/mls-c01-exap-prep-pass-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/mls-c01-exap-prep-pass-guide/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy: Photo by Green Chameleon on Unsplash
What is MLS-C01 and how is it helpful ? If you crack the MLS-C01 exam, I can assure you, it can help you in your role at your current company, may be a promotion or some other benefit. It definitely helped me to set myself apart from the crowd in my company, and helped me get a promotion as well. It depends on person to person and opportunities in company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How hyper-parameters impact model training?  (with MLS-C01 focus)</title>
      <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/ai-ml-hyperparameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/ai-ml-hyperparameters/</guid>
      <description>What are hyperparameters ? In simple terms, hyperparameters are a set of knobs you can tune before starting the learning process in machine learning. When set to a specific values, the model has a specific performance. When the hyperparameters are set to new values, the model gets new performance values.
What is performance of a model? In any machine learning process, we want to optimize the objective-function: a fancy name for a function that evaluates model predictions v/s values provided during training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Four Amazon Kinesis Streams Compared - Kinesis Data Stream vs Data Analytics Stream vs Firehose vs Video Stream</title>
      <link>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/ai-ml-kinesis-compare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sudo-code7.github.io/posts/tech/ml/mls-c01/ai-ml-kinesis-compare/</guid>
      <description>Ready reference for MLS-C01 and SAP-C01: Amazon Kinesis Streams Compared  No need to study and find out inputs and outputs supported by Kinesis Streams by digging into AWS Documentation Here is a ready to refer comparision of Kinesis streams available on AWS Score points in exam:  Know the right sources and sinks that each stream supports Be cautious about tricky exam questions that state a wrong answer option involving kinesis streams    Kinesis Video Streams - KVS  Though the name is Kinesis Video Streams, it supports ingestion of any kind of time series or time encoded data Video:  Stream video frames to KVS for storage, analytics, machine learning, playback or custom video processing Kinesis Video Streams provides fully-managed capabilities for HTTP Live Streaming (HLS) and Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (DASH).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
